<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-07-18T14:12:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Creating Placeholder Text</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/07/18/creating-placeholder-text.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/07/18/creating-placeholder-text.html</id>
    <published>2016-07-18T14:12:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-18T14:13:52-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Williamsburg DIY small batch, tousled bitters vice meh nesciunt neutra pabst. Ad
tempor cold-pressed, quis tofu ethical cliche. Polaroid squid helvetica
sartorial, jean shorts pariatur meggings. Proident readymade assumenda, kombucha
yuccie portland occupy DIY locavore. Aute vice cred selfies plaid. Placeat craft
beer elit, squid culpa roof party kitsch est. Enim sapiente crucifix normcore
pickled drinking vinegar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pariatur helvetica offal, enim excepteur narwhal bespoke sriracha craft beer
salvia cupidatat actually. Godard vinyl irure brunch, celiac seitan narwhal
fixie vice. Tofu pour-over flexitarian art party. Squid microdosing blue bottle
messenger bag dolor. Etsy pinterest disrupt, mustache +1 occaecat normcore viral
bespoke. Leggings taxidermy jean shorts normcore thundercats, four loko eu
proident ea. Cronut voluptate deserunt, delectus mixtape ethical pinterest
waistcoat nesciunt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Est mustache kickstarter, dolore eiusmod cupidatat vero craft beer meh.
Scenester esse flannel shoreditch craft beer hashtag. Enim irure ramps fashion
axe, taxidermy mumblecore post-ironic dolor. Semiotics thundercats direct trade
cornhole consequat. Vero brooklyn stumptown venmo, magna eiusmod farm-to-table
culpa next level chicharrones laboris ex lumbersexual. Gentrify bushwick
accusamus occupy, pour-over tacos banh mi tote bag assumenda hella tousled
deserunt. Sint twee kickstarter photo booth, letterpress put a bird on it offal
VHS keffiyeh ea mollit irony consectetur retro artisan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venmo twee shabby chic, bespoke minim direct trade paleo everyday carry ennui
laboris. Pour-over ullamco kinfolk biodiesel. XOXO farm-to-table kale chips,
deserunt skateboard banh mi slow-carb proident street art. Seitan fap normcore,
raw denim mustache food truck craft beer tattooed health goth ethical
kickstarter adipisicing pork belly. Pour-over veniam fanny pack, dolore yuccie
man braid hoodie semiotics plaid lomo esse in godard. Echo park next level
flannel, lo-fi sunt shoreditch try-hard freegan. Paleo kinfolk ut, et knausgaard
four dollar toast vice skateboard hella cliche williamsburg XOXO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gluten-free small batch tattooed seitan man bun. Placeat ethical dolore, aute
chartreuse fashion axe cold-pressed readymade dreamcatcher aesthetic voluptate.
Tote bag gochujang aliqua est, squid gentrify marfa VHS. Poutine PBR&amp;amp;B tumblr
skateboard, narwhal pabst echo park XOXO lumbersexual +1 accusamus cardigan.
Quinoa bicycle rights YOLO vice, aesthetic reprehenderit marfa ennui pitchfork.
Culpa voluptate ut nesciunt venmo vice, eiusmod ad affogato taxidermy shabby
chic cronut cold-pressed before they sold out ullamco. Schlitz listicle
chillwave tousled tattooed cold-pressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sint excepteur ad esse master cleanse, viral raw denim etsy aliquip culpa fap.
Tacos exercitation nostrud direct trade, quinoa austin sapiente. Voluptate kogi
marfa butcher. Meggings PBR&amp;amp;B sed, asymmetrical art party esse ex. Flexitarian
seitan single-origin coffee, small batch mixtape kinfolk salvia cardigan pug
culpa yr austin 8-bit scenester. Laborum fugiat accusamus hella, actually mlkshk
cold-pressed raw denim. Chartreuse tofu whatever, man braid brunch paleo
polaroid veniam mumblecore tacos plaid mollit exercitation esse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quis consectetur crucifix food truck leggings art party, pop-up trust fund. Twee
ut quinoa, fugiat raw denim venmo butcher sint. Banjo +1 fugiat schlitz pickled
swag, fingerstache bitters wolf single-origin coffee sapiente jean shorts.
Chillwave sunt ugh migas 8-bit, laborum pariatur cupidatat artisan. Yuccie small
batch PBR&amp;amp;B meggings helvetica 3 wolf moon authentic meh. Everyday carry ramps
kale chips meggings. XOXO freegan fingerstache vice, elit cold-pressed
farm-to-table gentrify velit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knausgaard affogato delectus, jean shorts chicharrones small batch before they
sold out occaecat selfies. Ea authentic kickstarter tumblr you probably haven&amp;rsquo;t
heard of them pinterest. Nisi PBR&amp;amp;B selfies, fixie normcore organic portland
lo-fi roof party kinfolk affogato retro wayfarers pitchfork. Brunch selvage
aesthetic helvetica dolor wolf. Cold-pressed put a bird on it leggings salvia.
Narwhal truffaut flexitarian, iPhone normcore shoreditch VHS ennui bushwick
pinterest exercitation dreamcatcher forage veniam. Lomo delectus mustache, ex
selfies everyday carry DIY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voluptate locavore laborum single-origin coffee ramps, accusamus chambray cred
paleo banh mi tousled meh meggings nihil. Tumblr nostrud exercitation, odio
pop-up polaroid umami actually truffaut whatever ugh keytar intelligentsia YOLO
helvetica. Authentic tumblr bushwick, aute bicycle rights bitters semiotics odio
voluptate. Flannel irure YOLO eiusmod polaroid taxidermy. Roof party etsy irure
letterpress banh mi meh. Quis iPhone authentic, messenger bag kitsch odio before
they sold out helvetica blue bottle offal beard williamsburg ullamco dolor
retro. Fanny pack cred ea tofu id yuccie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cronut bushwick deserunt, chillwave health goth officia cred occupy neutra.
Biodiesel selvage kickstarter, pug pour-over sed culpa cupidatat tilde butcher
PBR&amp;amp;B. Enim laborum asymmetrical mixtape, chicharrones chambray duis whatever
delectus consectetur forage. Pitchfork forage duis brunch before they sold out
meh, elit poutine umami twee. Deserunt normcore seitan pitchfork poutine.
Sartorial lumbersexual tempor, small batch pitchfork sriracha commodo ut
gluten-free ugh sapiente ad. Chambray drinking vinegar seitan semiotics, elit
quis duis tote bag neutra tofu locavore migas.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I Decided to Learn Software Development</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/05/14/why-i-decided-to-learn-software-development.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/05/14/why-i-decided-to-learn-software-development.html</id>
    <published>2016-05-14T11:12:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-18T14:06:43-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My journey to the Learn Verified program and learning software development has really been a journey of many steps.  I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed using and learning about technology, so technology has alway been a part of my life.  However, software development had always remained a bit of a mystery to me.  Sure I took a couple programming classes in college so I understood the basics, but in those types of classes you don&amp;rsquo;t make any of real value.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aftering graduating college and upon entering the workforce I found that effectively using technology was a good way to set myself apart from my peers.  But the technology I could use was limited to the Microsoft Office Suite.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found as I progresses through my career that knowing how to effectively technology can save a significant amount of time and energy.  This is particularly true when a significant amount of data is involved.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find the process of programming to be extremely engaging.  The process of breaking down a problem into it&amp;rsquo;s individual parts for me is both challenging and rewarding.  This processes has become a significant part of the way that I think.  Finding the individual steps for a task and then weighing the tradeoffs of possible solutions. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Middleman Blog with GitHub Pages</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2016/02/04/setting_up_middleman_with_github_pages.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2016/02/04/setting_up_middleman_with_github_pages.html</id>
    <published>2016-02-03T21:40:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-18T14:08:47-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Middleman is a static site generation framework with an available blog extension package.  I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to set up a blog with Middleman in the past, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always had trouble with deploying to GitHub pages.  To me it&amp;rsquo;s not as straight forward as it should be, but I think with a few tips it can easily be done.  Here are the steps that worked for me.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start off by creating a new Middleman Blog, change into the new directory and initialize a new git repo.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;middleman init snsavage.github.io --template&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;blog
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;snsavage.github.io/
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git init
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub Pages uses two different conventions depending on whether the pages are for a user, organization or a project.  User pages are created in a GitHub repo with a &lt;code&gt;username.github.io&lt;/code&gt; naming scheme and are served using files on the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch of that repo.  Project pages on the other hand use the &lt;code&gt;http(s)://&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io/&amp;lt;projectname&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; naming scheme and are served from the &lt;code&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; branch.  Here are the instructions for &lt;a title="GitHub Pages" href="https://pages.github.com"&gt;setting up your GitHub Pages repo&lt;/a&gt; and more &lt;a title="User, Organization, and Project Pages" href="https://help.github.com/articles/user-organization-and-project-pages/"&gt;detail on page types and naming conventions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you have setup your GitHub repo, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to add the remote to your local repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git remote add origin https://github.com/snsavage/snsavage.github.io.git
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because GitHub Pages use the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch for deploying your site, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to create a new branch for developing your site.  Understanding how this branch structure works with GitHub Pages is extremely important.  This is what caused most of my headaches.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new branch called &lt;code&gt;development&lt;/code&gt;, add the files to the repo and then commit the changes.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git checkout -b development
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git add .
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git commit -a -m &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"Initial Middleman Blog Setup"&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point your site should only have a &lt;code&gt;development&lt;/code&gt; branch.  Nothing was committed to the original &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch before creating the &lt;code&gt;development&lt;/code&gt; branch.  During my setup I created the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch and tested adding a file to that branch.  More information on manually creating pages can be found &lt;a title="Creating Project Pages Manually" href="https://help.github.com/articles/creating-project-pages-manually/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, create the new &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch as an &lt;a title="git-checkout Manual Page" href="https://git-scm.com/docs/git-checkout/1.7.3.1"&gt;orphan&lt;/a&gt; branch.  Then remove all files from that branch.  I also had to remove a directory that remained behind.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git checkout --orphan master
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git rm -rf .
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;rm -rf &lt;span class="nb"&gt;source&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, create an index.html file, add the file to the repo, commit the file and push to &lt;code&gt;origin&lt;/code&gt;.  As noted earlier, more on these steps can be found &lt;a title="Creating Project Pages Manually" href="https://help.github.com/articles/creating-project-pages-manually/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"My Page"&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt; index.html
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git add index.html
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git commit -a -m &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"First pages commit"&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git push origin master
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point your website should be live with the sample &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; page.  Your web address will be &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io&lt;/code&gt;.  But now that you know that isn&amp;rsquo;t working, it&amp;rsquo;s time to finish setting up Middleman.  Start by removing the &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git rm index.html
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to head back to the &lt;code&gt;development&lt;/code&gt; branch to finish the Middleman setup.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;git checkout development
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the Middleman Deploy extension to handle deploying to GitHub Pages.  The following instructions can be found &lt;a title="Middleman Deploy" href="https://github.com/middleman-contrib/middleman-deploy"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  As of this writing there is a typo in the Middleman Deploy &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve noted it below.     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add to your Gemfile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;gem &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'middleman-deploy'&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'~&amp;gt; 1.0'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the following lines to your &lt;code&gt;config.rb&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2
3
4
5&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;activate :deploy &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; |deploy|
  deploy.method &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; :git  &lt;span class="c"&gt;# This is shown as deploy.deploy_method in the README.&lt;/span&gt;
  deploy.remote &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"origin"&lt;/span&gt;
  deploy.branch &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"master"&lt;/span&gt;
end
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build and deploy your blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;table style="border-spacing: 0"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="gutter gl" style="text-align: right"&gt;&lt;pre class="lineno"&gt;1
2&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;middleman build
&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;middleman deploy
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the process that worked for me.  Please let me know if you have any feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
